

Grenoble, France

📳 (+33) 6 51 99 80 78 | 💌 hugo.bollon@proton.me | 🧌 hugobollon.me | 🖸 hbollon | 🛅 hugobollon | Driving license: B

## Summary.

Passionate software engineer specialized in Go and Open Source, with solid experience in backend development and DevOps engineering (Kubernetes, AWS, CI/CD). After several years designing and maintaining cloud platforms, I now wish to put my skills and motivation to work on high-impact projects as a Backend or Fullstack engineer.

## **Skills**

Languages Go, Python, Java, C/C++, JavaScript, TypeScript, Bash

Frontend Vue, Angular

**Backend** API REST, Gorm, Gin, Echo, Gorilla Mux

DevOps Kubernetes, Docker, Helm, ArgoCD, Pulumi, Terraform, GitOps, AWS (EKS, RDS, EC2, ECS, Fargate), IaC, CI/CD

**Database** PostgreSQL, SQLite, Neo4j **Environments** Linux, Git, GitHub Actions, GitLab CI

**Languages** French (native level), English B2 (TOEIC 905), Japanese A1 (learning)

## **Experience**

**Camptocamp SA** Chambéry, France

DEVOPS ENGINEER Sep. 2021 - Present

Design, automation, and maintenance of Kubernetes clusters with multiples cloud providers (AWS, Exoscale, Scaleway) using Infrastructure as Code (Pulumi, Terraform) for reliable and scalable platforms.

- Backend development in Go for internal tools, APIs, and automations. External open-source contributions (Terraform providers, Zitadel, etc.).
- Open-source lead for the Infrastructure department: management, maintenance, and evolution of Camptocamp Infrastructure Solutions' publicly licensed projects.
- · Design and management of CI pipelines to automate build, lint, test, and release stages, using Github Actions and Dagger.
- Implementation of CD pipelines based on GitOps practices with ArgoCD, ensuring automated, reproducible, and secure Kubernetes deployments.
- Containerization and orchestration of workloads: Docker image design, Docker Compose configuration, orchestrated deployments with Kubernetes, and containerized CI with Dagger.
- · Close collaboration with the Geospatial department: development of scripts and tools in Python and JavaScript (Vue 3, Angular), design of Helm charts, and optimization of Docker images for packaging and deploying their applications.
- Deployment and configuration of Monitoring, Logging, and Alerting solutions (Prometheus, Elastic, Grafana).
- Federated OIDC authentication via Keycloak and Zitadel.

**Camptocamp SA** Chambéry, France

Jun. 2021 - Sep. 2021 GO DEVELOPER INTERN

- Development and maintenance of Terraboard (Terraform observability tool).
- Migration of the frontend from AngularJS to Vue 3 / TypeScript.
- Backend API development in Go (Gorm, Gorilla Mux). • Writing unit tests and CI/CD automation.

**LAET - ENTPE** ANDROID DEVELOPER INTERN

· Native Android app (Java) for digitizing the Urbalog board game with multi-device support using Nearby Connections API.

### **Education**

**University Savoie Mont-Blanc** 

MSc Computer Science (with honours)

**University Savoie Mont-Blanc** 

BSc Computer Science (with honours)

High School of l'Albanais

SCIENTIFIC BACCALAUREATE (ISN)

Le-Bourget-Du-Lac, France

Le-Bourget-Du-Lac, France

2017 - 2020

Chambéry, France

Jan. 2020 - May 2020

Rumilly, France

2014 - 2017

#### Certifications

- **TOEIC**: 905/990 (Feb 2022) Listening: 440/495 (B2), Reading: 465/495 (C1)
- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner (June 2023) ID: PST3Q8DCVE41Q5GD

# **Strengths**

Takes initiative Self-taught Sociable Attentive to requirements Fast learner Team spirit